30 degrees north.
You should be able
to see it by now.
No kidding.
Sticks out like a sore thumb.
There’s nothing happening.
It’s awfully calm.
Well, be careful.
You never know.
Yoo-hoo!
Hi, Jeremie.
I don’t see anything
out of the ordinary in the tower.
Are you sure
it’s the right one?
That was what the scan picked up.
At least for a few seconds.
And you said you felt pulsations
a while ago, didn’t you?
I did.
Well, let’s say yes and no.
I’m not sure I did anymore.
I thought I did.
Okay, then.
(SCREAMING)
Sounds like Yumi!
What’s going on?
Can you hear me, Yumi?
Answer me!
Yumi?
Jeremie, Yumi’s disappeared.
What? Come on, she
couldn’t have just vanished.
Aelita, hold on.
I’ll get back to you.
Jeremie? Jeremie!
Hey, Yumi!
Yumi?
Hey, what’s wrong
with the hot chocolate today?
It tastes like dirty sweat socks
and an old pair of sneakers!
Odd the gourmet.
Yoo-hoo!
Hey, Ulrich!
Yoo-hoo! Yoo-hoo!
Well, what do you know.
Your fan club.
I don’t believe it!
Your darling Yumi has
deserted you for once?
Like your brain, huh?
It deserted you
a long time ago.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Hello? Oh, it’s you, Jeremie.
I recommend the hot chocolate.
Take my word for it.
Mhmm? What?
Okay, easy does it. That’s it.
Well, then.
What happened to her?
Well, she started
feeling sick…during recess.
It’s because she’s
been studying real hard.
Our teachers give us
way too much homework!
Alright. I’ll take care of her.
Now, back to class, all of you.
You heard what I said.
Now, go. Go on.
Well, feeling better, hm?
Hey!
No, no, no. Come on.
Lie down now, you hear?
Please, you need to rest!
Are you sure she
wasn’t hit by a laser?
Maybe there was a megatank
hiding somewhere.
No, no.
I would’ve seen it on the screen.
She still had all her life points
when she was devirtualized.
Well, in any case,
something abnormal happened.
Yeah, that’s for sure.
The proof is she passed out
in the scanner.
Normally,
the return trip’s pretty easy.
Huh, that’s what you think.
You ought to try it
one of these days.
You’ll love it!
Oh, Yumi!
Guess you’re feeling better, huh?
You had us scared.
Tell us what happened.
You sure you’re okay?
Yeah, I’m just tired.
Yumi, tell us what
happened on Lyoko.
Nothing, you hear?
Come on, let’s go
over to the factory now.
In your condition?
That’s a pretty crazy idea.
Hey, listen, we’ve got
more important things to do.
Like eating.
For example.
Hey…
What about Aelita?
Is she safe?
Yeah, I hope so.
I told her to stay in the tower.
I’ve got to go and check it out.
And you really can’t
remember what happened?
No, nothing.
Do you think it could’ve
come from the scanners?
A bug or something like that?
Unless it’s XANA trying out
a new way of attacking.
I haven’t the slightest idea.
I’m wondering
if all these transfers
aren’t becoming
a health problem.
Hey, do I smell fish,
or just cheap perfume?
You’re such a riot.
Ulrich…
what do you say we
get together after school, huh?
Get together with you?
Very tempting, but, uh, not.
You’re showing off
because Yumi’s here, huh?
Mademoiselle likes to keep
the competition as far away as she can.
That’s not true.
Why don’t you go out with her?
She’s really pretty.
Hey, you wouldn’t be trying
to make fun of me, would you?
No? Hah, great!
Thanks a lot, Yumi!
Ulrich…
I’ll be waiting for you
in the park after school! Ciao!
Hey, what are you
trying to pull anyway, huh?
Nothing. Go on, go out with her.
She’s been waiting
for this for ages. Go on.
Miss Ishiyama.
Come to my office right now.
But that thing wasn’t there before…
It looks like a guardian.
What’s going on with Yumi?
Is she mad at me or what?
I’ve never seen her like that.
She must’ve had
a really serious shock.
Ulrich!
What’s the big idea of
having a date with Sissi, huh!
This isn’t the time for that
you hear, Herb?
If you want an explanation,
go and ask Sissi.
Okay, I’ll leave you to
your love stories.
I’ve got a super-psychopathic
computer to feed.
Yumi, this is unspeakable.
Our poor Nurse Dorothy
is still very upset.
How could you have
done such a thing?
I’m giving you two hours
of detention in the library
to teach you a lesson.
Well, go on.
There’s something
troubling you, Yumi.
Care to tell me about it?
Yumi, I’m here to help you--
that’s part of my job.
Very well.
Keep this up and I’ll have to
inform your parents
about the way you’re behaving.
Not my parents.
That’s enough now, Miss Ishiyama.
What! But…
Get your hand
off the phone right now!
Not my parents!
I won’t warn you again.
Yumi, if you keep this up
I’ll suspend you!
No!
Hello there, Yumi!
As soon as I got
close to the monsters,
they started to shoot.
You shouldn’t have
left the tower, Aelita.
I know.
You’re not too
mad at me, are you?
Mad? No.
Besides, I think you made
an important discovery.
This could have something to do
with what happened to Yumi.
Should I go back there?
No, hold on.
I’ll send Ulrich and Odd as backup.
Jeremie, what happened to Yumi
might happen to one of
your friends or both of them.
If they came to Lyoko now,
it could be very dangerous for them.
I guess you’re right.
Go on, then, but promise me
you’ll be careful.
You know me.
Oh, it’s you.
What did the principal want?
We have to go to the factory now.
Oh, no. Forget it.
First of all, there’s no reason to go.
And second, you have to rest.
I have to go to the scanner room.
No.
Nobody’s going back to Lyoko
until I give the order.
It’s too dangerous.
I’ve got some tests I have to run first.
Hey…
it’s important, you hear?
I have to go back
to the scanner room.
Er…Yumi, what are you trying to…
Shh.
There.
I, uh…
I’m not sure it’s a good idea--
you should go home
and get some rest!
Come on, take me
to the scanner room.
Uh b-b-b-b-but
you should go home
and take a bath!
No, a cold shower!
Very cold!
Very, very, very cold
to calm you down!
Jeremie, hurry up,
we’ve got to get going--
Ulrich, no wait!
It’s not what you think!
I swear, Ulrich, wait!
Bravo.
Okay, time to go.
And we can also observe
cases of parthenogenesis
among certain insects.
This phenomenon
is relatively common
and comparable to
a sort of natural cloning.
That is to say the animal
gives birth to a replica of itself--
an exact replica with
no differences between them.
Scientists have succeeded
in employing this process with rabbits.
Alright, we’ll continue
with this subject tomorrow.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
Ulrich, you have to listen.
I don’t want to listen to you.
Something’s not right with Yumi.
She’s not in her normal state.
I don’t know what she’s been through,
but she’s traumatized.
Okay. Let’s go.
Oh, no.
What do you think
this phenomenon is?
I wish I could tell you,
but I have no idea.
Aelita’s checking it out.
It could be XANA’s doing.
I forgot to lock the door.
All my equipment!
You think Sissi’s behind all this?
Why would she want to do it?
Hey, maybe it’s Herb.
He sure was mad
when we saw him today.
Wait, who was the last one
to leave this room?
Oh, no.
No, that’s impossible. Not Yumi.
You’ve got to admit
she’s been acting weird lately.
Okay.
Yumi hasn’t been
herself lately, that’s right,
but still, the enemy is XANA.
Jeremie’s right.
XANA’s launched an attack.
and I’m sure all this other stuff
is to distract us
while he’s calmly and quietly
getting rid of Aelita.
Aelita!
She’s all alone on Lyoko,
and we can’t get to her!
Are we going to
the scanner room?
Yeah, let’s go.
Go on, do your stuff, Jeremie.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Transfer Ulrich.
Transfer Odd.
Transfer Yumi.
Scanner Odd.
Scanner Ulrich.
Scanner Yumi.
Virtualization.
Where’s Yumi?
What? She’s not with you?
No, she wasn’t transferred.
Over there!
Laser arrow!
Hurry, we’ve got to go and free Yumi.
Yumi? Yumi’s not…
The real Yumi.
The one who’s here on Lyoko.
The other one was created by XANA.
Jeremie, whatever you do,
don’t go anywhere near Yumi.
Do you hear me, Jeremie?
Jeremie!
Yumi!
What are you doing!
Now!
Laser arrow!
(CACKLES)
Y-a-a-a-a-h!
It’s a guardian.
A sort of digital jail adapted
to the body imprisoned in it.
I can’t destroy it with my weapons.
I can create a clone--
a false image of Yumi.
We can try to convince
the guardian that he’s mistaken.
Okay, let’s go.
(CELESTIAL HUMMING)
Oh, wow! Piece of cake!
Yumi.
What? What happened?
Sorry, no time to explain.
We’ve got to deactivate the tower.
Jeremie’s not responding.
I don’t understand.
I have the feeling
that something’s wrong.
He’s all alone with the other one.
If she destroys the scanner, it’s all over.
The other? The other what?
Who wants to wreck the scanner?
The other you.
What if something
has happened to Jeremie?
And what if we don’t manage
to deactivate the tower in time?
This is serious. Listen, one of us has to
go back to reality and right away.
We don’t have much time.
Right. I’ll go.
No, it’s better if I go.
I don’t know how many
life points I have left, Ulrich,
and if I only have five or ten,
I won’t be of much use to you here.
And also, I have a little matter
to deal with that only I can settle.
It’s between me and myself.
Then you go.
But first you have to
devirtualize yourself.
The question is how.
You’re armed, aren’t you?
You know what?
You look just like me
when I’m having a bad day.
Uh-oh. We’ve got company.
Odd, watch out.
On your right.
How many life points do I have left?
I don’t know, but it’s
got to be less than 10 by now.
Yumi!
I’m still here?
Well, I guess I messed up
on my calculations.
You always were
a washout in math.
Right, but thanks to you
I can count to three.
Aaaah!
Triplicate!
Fusion.
Aelita, you’re up.
Aaah!
(CACKLES)
Oh, no!
Aaaaah!
That’s fantastic!
The fact that XANA was able to
materialize another Yumi
proves one thing.
It proves that materialization
is really possible.
That’s crazy!
XANA’s helping us
with our materialization research!
Back to work then, Einstein.
No sweat.
I’ll start programming again right now.
But why bother?
If I were you, I’d go and see XANA.
He’s got the answer, so ask him!
I wouldn’t trust him.
Look at the Yumi he sent us.
Oh, yeah? She wasn’t
that different from the original.
She sure was!
She didn’t fool me.
I saw the difference as soon as
she started to flirt with me.
Really? Are you sure?
Do you have any proof that it’s
the real me you’re looking at?
What are you doing?
Uh, no. Cut it out.
I’ve had enough of that for one day.
You’re not jealous are you, Ulrich?
Sure looks like it!
(LAUGHING)
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO